Now we will run Docker commands and understand how each of them work.
First of all open command prompt window and make sure your Docker desktop is running.
Check it on the taskbar to be sure it's running.
Now on command prompt also known as CMD type Docker space ps and enter.
This will show all the running containers on your local PC.
Right now there are none and so it's not showing any one of them.
You can also check the containers from the Docker desktop app.
Click the container tab on the left to see all the containers.
Currently there are none and Docker desktop is also showing no containers.
Let's create a container containing you want to Linux operating system.
So I have a question for you, where are we supposed to get this?
You want to OS from you want to website, right?
Absolutely wrong.
We will have to get you want to OS Docker image and that we can download from Docker Hub website.
Open Docker Hub on your browser.
Then search for you pun two.
The first result of you pun two showing text, Docker official images is the one you have
to click.
On the right portion you will see Docker pull command, just copy it and paste it on your
CMD window press enter.
Do you know how to paste on command prompt?
You just right click the mouse button and it will paste the copied text.
So the command will download the you pun two image from Docker Hub to your local machine.
Just wait for one two minutes and now the you pun two images downloaded on our local machine.
Confirm this on Docker desktop by clicking the images section to find the you pun two image.
Now on CMD type Docker images command and press enter this will show all the images present
on our Docker server.
It showing the you pun two image, understanding image tags.
The copy the Docker pull command in order to download you pun two image on our PC.
Notice after the image name there is colon resolute dash 20 25 11 30 this thing is the
image tag image tag is a label to identify a specific version of it Docker image within
a repository on the you pun two page click on the text section.
There are multiple versions of you pun two image distinguished by different tags.
One is resolute another one is devil.
Let's copy devil tag paste it on the command window of the colon.
Then press enter to pull this devil tag image of you pun two it has downloaded now check
it on Docker desktop we can see it there now we change the tag to latest and press enter
the latest tag image of you pun two is downloaded the latest tag image is the most recently
pushed version of the image in every positive it means it is the latest version of you
pun two image also the latest tag in Docker image references the default tag assigned
to an image if no specified tag is provided to it let us now run the you pun two image
from Docker container the command to use this Docker run
enter cmt window type Docker space run space dash dash name space and then specified the container name.
I am naming the container you see after that type dash IT the IT tag tells Docker to
start an interactive batch session within the you pun two container give a space then
type the image with its tag which is you bun two colon resolute dash 20 25 11 30 we can copy
this tag from Docker desktop also give a space then type slash bin slash bash and
press enter the you pun two container is created with you pun two image and we are now
inside the best session we can check the container in the Docker desktop
inside the best session we can enter line next commands like ls which shows all the
directories inside you pun pose OS type OMI and press enter this line next command shows
the username of T current user which is removed next type exit and press enter this will
exit the best session check the Docker desktop now and you will find the container is
exited it's now better to remove this container and free some space so type Docker space
Rm followed by uc which is the name of the container this will delete the uc container
from our machine confirm this on Docker desktop which shows the container is indeed deleted
before we end this lecture one more thing needs to be told on the Docker desktop delete
all images now on tcmt again run the same Docker command that we previously ran
now this time we do not have the you pun tools image on our local machine so it gave
T message unable to find the image then it starts downloading from the Docker hub registry
the image is downloaded and the container is created and in running state confirm this
on Docker desktop also